(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
はい！というわけで！
Alright! So!
みんな見えてますかー？
Can everyone see me?
今日は紫咲シオン三周年ということで...
Today is Murasaki Shion's 3rd anniversary...
みんな、見えてるー？
Everyone, are you watching?
今日は生誕祭ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to today's birthday celebration live!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、みなさんありがとうございました。
Alright, thank you very much everyone.
本当にね、今日は誕生日お祝いしていただいて、最高の誕生日になった。
Seriously, having my birthday celebrated today, it's been the best birthday.
本当に楽しかった。マジでありがとう。
It was really fun. Thank you so much.
見てくれたみんなもありがとう！
And thank you to everyone who watched!
Murasaki Shion
4th Anniversary LIVE
is about to
start
うらぱっぱ 馬鹿見てないで
Urappa-ppa, don't look like an idiot
うらぱっぱっぱらりら 踊れよ
Urappa-ppa-pararira, just dance
魔界脱走の優等生
The honor student who escaped the demon world
華やかな我儘 讃えよ
Praise this glamorous selfishness
いないいないばぁで こっち向いて
Peek-a-boo, look this way
したたかな未来を咲かせよ
Let a sturdy future bloom
仕合待って 高まって
Waiting for the match, getting excited
たまーにパワー放て黒魔術
Occasionally release power, black magic
せーの！で此処に集えよ
One, two! Gather here
闇に震えケルベロス
Cerberus trembling in the darkness
刹那に響く言葉は
The words that echo in an instant
ぶち切れ発狂パラダイス
Are a snap-and-go-crazy paradise
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
これからも私の元で
Stay by my side from now on too
不思議な力打ち放って
Release the mysterious power
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
And the world will start smiling
うらぱっぱっぱらりら歌えば
If we sing 'urappappa-pararira'
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
暗い面してないで
Don't look so gloomy
なまった体 さぁ 踊れよ
Come on, dance with that stiff body
視界外 目逸らさないで
Don't look away from my sight
今はただ離れていかないで
For now, just don't go away
やや待って こっち向いて
Wait a bit, look this way
今はまだ心の準備を
I'm still preparing my heart
期待猜疑で固まって
Frozen with expectation and suspicion
うらぱっぱっぱ 動け黒魔術
Urappappa, move, black magic
我に続け 今宵よ
Follow me tonight
闇を破れメシアよ
Break the darkness, O Messiah
討つべき者 その名は
The one to strike, that name is...
眠りの発症パラダイス
The onset of sleep paradise
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
白黒つけてあげるから
Because I'll make things clear
不思議な力振りかざして
Brandish the mysterious power
みんなで笑顔になっちゃって
And let's all smile together
うらぱっぱっぱらりら歌えば
If we sing 'urappappa-pararira'
一生一緒かもね
Maybe we'll be together forever
ひらりひらりと紫に染まって
Fluttering and fluttering, dyed in violet
これからも貴方の元で
From now on too, by your side
奇跡の呪文解き放って
Release the miracle incantation
咲かせる笑顔の花を
Let the flowers of smiles bloom
キラリ心奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach the depths of my heart
これからも変わらないままで
Staying unchanged from now on too
不思議な力 ほら 宿って
Look, the mysterious power dwells within
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
And the world will start smiling
うらぱっぱっぱらりら歌えば
If we sing 'urappappa-pararira'
一生一緒だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
絶対一緒だよね
Definitely together forever, right?
はい！ということで！
Yes! And so!
紫咲シオン4周年記念ライブ！イェーイ！
Murasaki Shion 4th Anniversary LIVE! Yay!
このね、出てると思いますけど画面の端に。どっち？こっちかな？
I think it's appearing at the edge of the screen. Which side? This side?
こっちだー！出てる通り、ハッシュタグ紫咲シオン4周年記念で是非いっぱいツイートしてください。
It's this side! As shown, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #Murasaki Shion 4th Anniversary Celebration.
スクショもね、いっぱい撮ってね。
Take lots of screenshots too, okay?
はい、なんと4周年らしいです。ね、びっくりだよね。
Yes, apparently it's the 4th anniversary. It's surprising, isn't it?
だって5年目に入っちゃうわけでしょ？
Because I'm entering my 5th year, right?
5年ってさ、普通に考えてヤバいよな。なんか5ってキリが良いから。
5 years, if you think about it, is amazing. 5 is such a good milestone.
ま、まだ4年、4年なんですけど。
Well, it's still 4 years, just 4 years though.
いや凄い本当に。長いようで短かった気がする。
It's really amazing. It feels like it was long yet short.
ね、サムネもね、見て後ろにあるんだけど。遠いな。
Look at the thumbnail too, it's behind me. It's far.
遠いけど、後ろにある通りめちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょ？
It's far, but as you can see behind me, isn't it super cute?
ね、このサムネに映ってる通りですね、なんと！
Just as shown in this thumbnail, guess what!
ゲストが3人来てくれてます！楽しみだね。
Three guests have come! I'm looking forward to it.
あ！早速ゲストの1人目が来てるみたい。
Oh! It looks like the first guest is already here.
うわあああ！
Whoaaaa!
可愛い、見て！
Look, how cute!
ねえ赤ちゃん、
Look, it's a baby.
ちょっと赤ちゃん...
A little baby...
今日からママになります。
I'm going to be a mom starting today.
ねえみんなこれ重大発表ですこれ。
Hey everyone, this is a major announcement.
ママになりました。
I've become a mom.
嘘です。
I'm lying.
赤ちゃん、赤ちゃん殴って炎上しちゃう。
I'll get canceled for hitting a baby.
可愛い、マジで可愛いこいつ。
Cute, he's really cute.
みんなだよ、でも。
It's all of you, though.
やばい、リスナー抱いてるこれ。
Oh no, I'm holding a listener.
リスナーバイバイ。
Bye-bye, listener.
あはははは、リスナーバイバイ。
Ahahahaha, bye-bye listener.
可愛いしおっこマジで可愛い。
Cute Shiokkos, you're really cute.
ねえステージのここにもちょこんとね、
ね、両端にいるんだよこれ。
Look, there are some sitting right here on the stage,
on both ends.
ちょっと見えないかも、ここここ。
You might not be able to see them, but they're right here.
可愛い、このステージめっちゃ綺麗だなマジで。
プラネタリウムみたい。
So cute. This stage is seriously beautiful.
It's like a planetarium.
はい、というわけでね、このあともまだまだ曲が
たくさん続くのでぜひ楽しんでください。
All right, well, there are still plenty of songs to come,
so please enjoy them.
なんと！そして最後に重大告知もあります！
And! There's also a major announcement at the end!
最後までちゃんと見て、ちゃんと、ちゃんとずっと
一秒たりとも目を離さず見てください！
Make sure to watch until the very end. Don't take
your eyes off for even a second!
次は... ゲストが来てます！もう。
Next up... we have a guest! Already.
というわけで、行こう！
So, let's go!
魔法少女とチョコレゐト
作詞・作曲：ピノキオピー
Magical Girl and Chocolate
Lyrics/Composition: PinocchioP
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
純粋が無駄になる世界で
In a world where purity goes to waste
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
また来週も戦えるかな
I wonder if I can fight again next week
可愛い正義を纏って　決めポーズで光って
Donning cute justice, shining in a signature pose
ピュアな想い　魔法に変えて
Turning pure feelings into magic
みんなの平和願って　邪悪に立ち向かって
Wishing for everyone's peace, confronting evil
それを匿名はディスった
And some anonymous person dissed it
本当は　何でしょう　ぶっちゃけ　何でしょう
What is it, really? To be blunt, what is it?
自分が尊いからみんなに　出会って欲しいんでしょ
You just want everyone to see how precious you are, right?
そんな手垢のついた　よくある不評で
With such worn-out, commonplace criticism
錆びつく魔法の適性
My aptitude for magic is rusting away
知らん　知らん
I don't know, I don't know
はー正直もうやめたい　魔法少女やめたい
Ah, honestly I want to quit, I want to quit being a magical girl
誰が敵か味方か　わかんないし
I don't even know who's a friend or a foe
陰険で　強欲で　滑稽で　軽度で
Insidious, greedy, comical, and superficial
魔法が解けるチョコみたいに
Like chocolate that loses its magic
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
純粋が無駄になる世界で
In a world where purity goes to waste
はー正直もうやめたい　魔法少女やめたい
Ah, honestly I want to quit, I want to quit being a magical girl
もう好きな人だけ守っていたい
I just want to protect the people I like
ヤン・ダンダンディダン・ダンダンダディダン
Yan dandan didan dandand adidan
無意識に這い寄る魔力が見えたぜ
I saw magical power crawling in unconsciously
不満で探したポーションがバリバリ
The potion I searched for in frustration is crackling
お前ら　何でしょう　性根が　何でしょう
What's with you guys? What's with your nature?
怒りに任せのナイフで　しちゃうんでしょ
You're going to strike with a knife fueled by anger, right?
やり返しなんてさ　次々に闇を産むんです
Retaliation just creates darkness one after another
光失ったあの日
That day when I lost the light
腐る　腐る
Rotting, rotting
はー正直もうやめたい　魔法少女やめたい
Ah, honestly I want to quit, I want to quit being a magical girl
視聴者の期待に応えるたびに
Every time I meet the expectations of the viewers
完璧で　精進で　洗練で　潔白で
Perfect, diligent, refined, and innocent
嘘で固めたチョコみたいに
Like chocolate hardened by lies
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
甘い味がやみつきでしょう
The sweet taste is addictive, isn't it?
はー正直もうやめたい　魔法少女やめたい
Ah, honestly I want to quit, I want to quit being a magical girl
辞めないでって言われるの期待してない
I'm not expecting you to tell me not to quit
ファンの善意の　もう
The fans' good intentions, already...
心配してる　もう
Are worrying me, already...
全てに耳を塞いでしまったの
I've blocked out everything
はー正直もうやめたい　魔法少女やめたい
Ah, honestly I want to quit, I want to quit being a magical girl
誰が敵か味方か　わかんないし
I don't even know who's a friend or a foe
陰険で　強欲で　滑稽で　軽度で
Insidious, greedy, comical, and superficial
魔法が解けるチョコみたいに
Like chocolate that loses its magic
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
魔法で最低な日を上書きしそう
Looks like I'll overwrite the worst days with magic
はー正直もうやめたい　魔法少女やめたい
Ah, honestly I want to quit, I want to quit being a magical girl
自分ごと消えちゃってさようなら
Fading away with myself, goodbye
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
純粋が無駄になる世界で
In a world where purity goes to waste
ヤン・ラリパッパッパッパッパッバラ
Yan raripappappappappappabara
また来週も見てくれるかな
I wonder if you'll watch again next week
はい、というわけで魔法少女とチョコレゐトでしたー！
All right, that was 'Magical Girl and Chocolate'!
はーい！
Yeah!
あのさ...
You know...
はい。
Yes.
あのさ...
You know...
何ですか？
What is it?
あのさ... から始まるMCある？
Is that how an MC starts? With 'You know...'?
あのさ、
Hey...
なんですが？
What is it?
二人でさ、配信するのいつぶりか知ってる？
Do you know how long it's been since we last streamed together?
配信っていうか、こうやって喋ってるの、
Well, rather than a stream, just talking like this...
いつぶりなんですか？
...how long has it been?
いつぶり？いつぶり？
How long? How long?
1年ぶりらしいよ。
Apparently, it's been a year.
えーー！
Eeeh!
1、1年ぶり！？
A-A year?!
びっくりだよね。
Surprising, isn't it?
いや、やばいね。普通にびっくり。
No way. I'm genuinely surprised.
そうだよ、だってアクシオちゃんだよ。
Right, because it's Akushio.
うわ、懐かしいな、アクシオちゃんのあの名シーン。
Whoa, how nostalgic, that famous scene of Akushio.
名シーンって何？全然覚えてないんだけど。
What famous scene? I don't remember at all.
一番の名シーンよ。
The most famous scene.
いや全然覚えてないんだ。もう1年経つし記憶が...
I really don't remember. It's been a year, so my memory...
アティシガニでしょ。
It's Atishigani, right?
ん？なんですかそれは？
Hm? What is that?
なんですかそれは？まあそれは一旦置いておきましょう。
What is that? Well, let's put that aside for now.
いやいやいや。
Wait, wait, wait.
やめておきましょう。私わからないので。
Let's stop. I don't know what it is.
でもさっき言ってたじゃん、公式になったって。
But you said earlier that it became official.
公式っていうか、そうね、ガオ先生の...
Official... well, Gao-sensei's...
コミケのグッズに、アティシガニがなんか出てたみたいで。
Comiket goods seemed to have Atishigani on them.
私全然わかんないんですけど。
I don't understand it at all.
何のことか。
...what that's about.
あなたはカニになったんだよ。
You've become a crab.
カニになった！？なりたくてなったわけじゃないんだよ。
I've become a crab?! It's not like I wanted to become one.
なれたんだよ、やっと。
You finally became one.
いやだから、勝手に成らされたんだよ、あの1時間の配信の中で。
No, I was forced into it during that one-hour stream.
入れ替わりのタイミングだったよね。
It was at the timing of the body swap, right?
一番良かった、あのシーンが。
That scene was the best.
忘れない、あの時のこと。
I won't forget that time.
感動的なね、歌の最中に。
A touching moment, right in the middle of a song.
そうよ。
That's right.
ぜひね、見たことない人はぜひ、あの、アクシオちゃんの3Dライブ見てみてください。
Please, if you haven't seen it, definitely check out Akushio's 3D live.
ぜひ見てください、感動するんで。
Please watch it, it's really touching.
あのシーン。
That scene.
しないわ。ギャグだよ、ギャグ。
It's not. It's a gag, a gag.
いやでもね、まあ、あの、この『魔法少女とチョコレゐト』
But, well, this song, "Magical Girl and Chocolate"...
この曲ね、なんと... あ、ちょっと話変えちゃうんですけど。
...this song, actually... Ah, I'm changing the subject.
はい、何でしょう。
Yes, what is it?
この曲ね、私思うことがあって。
About this song, there's something on my mind.
なんかちょっとさ、この曲なんか誰かとシオンちゃん歌ってなかった？
Like, didn't you sing this song with someone else before, Shion-chan?
え、初めて歌ったよ。
Eh, this is my first time singing it.
いやちょっと待って、私、今、記憶が... このライブのために一生懸命聴いて覚えて、
Wait, my memory... I listened and practiced so hard for this live...
アクアちゃんのために。
...for Aqua-chan's sake.
結構前に『歌ってみた』動画で、あの、にじさんじの星川さんと...
Quite a while ago, in a "tried singing" video, with Hoshikawa-san from Nijisanji...
...なんか歌ってた記憶があるんですけど。
...I have a memory of you singing it.
いやー、ちょっと... ないよそんなの。
No, I... there's no such thing.
いやー、私の記憶が正しければ...
Well, if my memory is correct...
アクアちゃんと歌いたくて、アクアちゃんのために覚えて、
I wanted to sing it with Aqua-chan, so I learned it for her.
アクアちゃんと初めて今ここで歌ったよ。
I just sang it with Aqua-chan for the first time here.
え、ちなみにパートも、なんか星川のパートを私が歌わされてて、
And by the way, the parts... I was made to sing Hoshikawa's part.
あの、星川の代わりみたいになってる気がするんだけど。
I feel like I've become Hoshikawa's substitute.
いや、なわけないじゃん。アクアちゃんしかいないよ。
No, that's impossible. There's only Aqua-chan.
アクアちゃんのために歌い分けも一生懸命考えて、
I thought hard about the part distribution for Aqua-chan's sake.
「ここアクアちゃんが歌ったほうがいい」とか。
"It's better if Aqua-chan sings here," and so on.
歌い分けに関して、本当は「星川」って書いてある部分を...
About the distribution, the parts where it originally said "Hoshikawa"...
「アクア」って直して、そのまま引用して...
...you changed to "Aqua" and used them as they were...
なわけ... なん、なん、なわけないじゃん、そんなわけ。
No way... No, no, that's impossible, no way.
いいや、私は星川の代わりなんですね、所詮。
No, I'm just Hoshikawa's substitute after all.
所詮、代わり者なんですね。
After all, I'm just a replacement.
アクアしかいないよ。
There's only Aqua.
誰でもいいんだ。
Anyone would do.
アクアしかいないよ、こうやって。
There's only Aqua, see?
私にはアクアしかいないよ。
I only have Aqua.
言ったね？
You said it.
言った、言った、言った。
I said it, I said it, I said it.
絶対だからね。
You better mean it.
私、後でYouTube見て、あの、星川と歌ってる動画あったら、マジで削除申請めっちゃするからね。
If I check YouTube later and find a video of you singing with Hoshikawa, I'm going to file so many deletion requests.
星川さんのは非公開にしてもらって、一旦。
I'll have Hoshikawa-san's made private for now.
いや、あれも、あれで可愛かったです。
Well, that one was cute in its own way.
あ、聴いてくれたんだ。歌ってないけど。
Oh, you listened to it. Even though I didn't sing it.
え、YouTubeに上がってる気がするけど、歌ってないけど聴いてくれたんだね。
Eh, I feel like it's on YouTube, but you listened even though I didn't sing it, right?
聴きました。
I listened to it.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いや、すごい良かった。今回一緒に歌えて本当に良かったよ。
It was really good. I'm truly glad we could sing together this time.
うん、ありがとう、本当に。
Yeah, thank you, really.
あとね、『迷宮のアクア色』もマジで良かった、1曲目の。
Also, "Meikyuu no Aqua-iro" was really good too, the first song.
あ、『紫パレット』ね。
Ah, "Murasaki Palette," right.
ん？
Hm?
『紫パレット』。
"Murasaki Palette."
何その曲？何その曲名？
What's that song? What's that song title?
あ、あの…
Ah, um...
あの、あの曲…
Um, that song...
『紫苑色パレット』って言うんですか？
Is it called 'Shion-iro Palette'?
それ、『紫苑色パレット』って言うんだよ。
Yeah, that's 'Shion-iro Palette'.
あれいいよね、あれ。
That's a good one, isn't it?
あれ好きなの。
I like that one.
『#メイドのあくあいろ』は？
How about 'Maid of Aqua-color'?
あれは、あくあちゃんのオリ曲でしょ？
That one's Aqua-chan's original song, right?
あれ？あれ？
Oh? Oh?
「ねぇもっと」のやつでしょ？
The one with "Hey, more," right?
そう、「ねぇもっと」のやつ。あれは『紫苑色パレット』…
Yeah, the "Hey, more" one. That was 'Shion-iro Palette'...
あれは『#メイドのあくあいろ』。
That was 'Maid of Aqua-color'.
じゃあ「ルパパパパパパパパルラララ」のやつは？
Then what about the "Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa" one?
あ、ずびだばのやつは？
Ah, the "Zu-bi-da-ba" one?
あくあいろ… あれ？
Aqua-color... wait?
あれ？あれ？
Wait? Wait?
めちゃくちゃになってんじゃん！
It's a total mess!
いや、すごい可愛かったよ。
No, it was really cute.
ね、ありがとう。
Yeah, thanks.
これからね、どんどん多分、ゲストの人も出るのかな？
I guess more guests will be appearing from now on?
出る出る。
They will, they will.
ちょっと楽しみですね。
I'm looking forward to it.
ちょっと見てますよ。
I'll be watching.
はい。
Okay.
シオンには…
For Shion...
君だけだよ。
...it's only you.
ふふふ。
Hehehe.
適当なこと言ってんじゃねーよ。
Don't just say whatever comes to mind.
帰りな！
Go home already!
じゃあね！
See ya!
じゃあね、あくあちゃん。
See ya, Aqua-chan.
え？ちょっと待って、違う、違う。
Eh? Wait a second, no, no.
違う、違う、違う、違う。待って、あなたが帰ったらどうするの、ここ！
No, no, no, no. Wait, what am I supposed to do if you leave?!
え？
Eh?
私に、私に… バイバイ！
I... I... Bye bye!
バイバイ〜。
Bye bye~
言って。 作詞・作曲：n-buna
Say it. Lyrics/Composition: n-buna
あのね、
You know,
私 実は気付いてるの
I've actually noticed
ほら、君が言ったこと
Look, the things you said
あまり
I can't believe
考えてないと、思えなくて
That you didn't think about them
忘れてたんだけど
Though I'd forgotten
盲目的に
Blindly,
盲動的に
Recklessly,
妄想的に生きて
Living delusionally
衝動的な
Impulsive,
焦燥的な
Impatient,
消極的なままじゃ駄目だったんだ
Being passive just wouldn't do
きっと、人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
I'm sure I'll think about it before my life's final day
全部、全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
It's a shame I won't be able to say it all
ああ、いつか人生最後の日、君がいないことを
Ah, that someday on my life's final day, you won't be there
もっと、
More,
ちゃんと、
Properly,
言って。
Say it.
あのね、
You know,
空が青いのってどうやって
How should I tell you
伝えればいいんだろうね
That the sky is blue?
夜の
How can I make
雲が高いのってどうすれば
You understand how high
君もわかるんだろう
The night clouds are?
言って。
Say it.
あのね、
You know,
私 実はわかってるの
I actually understand now
もう、君が言ったこと
The things you said
あのね、
You know,
わからず屋って言うんだろうね
I guess you'd call me stubborn
忘れたいんだけど
Though I want to forget
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
Tell me more clearly
忘れないようメモしてよ
Make a memo so I won't forget
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's meet at the platform tomorrow at 10
牡丹は散っても花だ
A peony is still a flower after it falls
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Remembrance is keen even after summer leaves
口に出して、
Say it aloud,
声に出して
Give it a voice
君が言って。
You say it.
そして、人生最後の日、君が見えるのなら
And if I can see you on my life's final day
きっと、人生最後の日も愛を歌うのだろう
I'm sure I'll sing of love even then
全部、全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
Because I'll say it wasn't all for nothing
ああ、いつか人生最後の日、君がいないことを
Ah, that someday on my life's final day, you won't be there
言いたいことが
Things I want to say
まだ信じられないけど
I still can't believe them, but
もっと もっと
More, more
もっと
More
君が
You...
もっと もっと
More, more
もっと
More
ちゃんと 言って
Say it clearly
はい、「言って。」でした。
Yes, that was "Say It."
めちゃめちゃね、映像が綺麗だったの。
The visuals were so incredibly beautiful.
見てました、みんな？見てた？
Were you watching, everyone? Did you see it?
空がね、青いのってどうやって伝えたらいいんだろうね。
How should I describe how blue the sky was?
でも青くて綺麗だった。マジで映像めっちゃ綺麗だった。
But it was blue and beautiful. Seriously, the visuals were so gorgeous.
はい、「言って。」はね、シオンのちょっと思い出のある曲で、
Yes, "Say It" is a song with some special memories for me,
あの本家のね、PVもめっちゃあの素敵なので、みんな聴いてみてください。
and the original music video is really wonderful, so please check it out.
次はなんだろうな、なんだろうな。
What's next? I wonder what it is.
次はコラボです。
Next is a collaboration.
どうぞ。
Here it is.
Oh my God
愛のネタバレ別れっぽいな
Love spoilers, feels like a breakup
人生のネタバレ死ぬっぽいな
Life spoilers, feels like death
何それ卑屈に死んでかっこいいじゃん
What's that? Dying submissively is pretty cool, isn't it?
それっぽい単語集で踊ってんだ失敬
Dancing to a collection of "cool" words, excuse me
神っぽいな
God-ish
作詞・作曲・編曲：ピノキオピー
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: PinocchioP
神っぽいな
It's God-ish
もいぜ もいぜ それ もいぜ もいぜ 逆に興奮してきたな
Moisé, Moisé, that's Moisé, Moisé, conversely I'm starting to get excited
おきね おきね 夢 おきね おきね 景気いいけど人生は修行
Wake up, wake up, dream won't wake, won't wake, things look good but life is asceticism
ご愁傷様
My condolences
神っぽいなそれ 卑屈 神っぽいなそれ
That's God-ish, submissive, that's God-ish
My God I want you, want you IQが下がっていく感じ
My God I want you, want you, the feeling of IQ dropping
邪視っぽいなそれ 卑屈 邪視っぽいなそれ
That's evil-eye-ish, submissive, that's evil-eye-ish
My God I hate you, hate you 害虫はどっち
My God I hate you, hate you, which one is the pest?
その髪型 その目 その口元 その香水 その服 そのメイク
That hairstyle, those eyes, that mouth, that perfume, those clothes, that makeup
あれっぽいなそれ 卑屈 あれっぽいなそれ
That's that-ish, submissive, that's that-ish
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That quote, that opinion, that criticism, that charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいなそれ 卑屈 ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃうわ
That's God-ish, submissive, -ish, -ish, I'm starting to admire it
神っぽいな
It's God-ish
メタ思考する本質は悪意 人を小馬鹿にしたような作為
The essence of meta-thinking is malice, an artifice like making a fool of others
無意に生き延びるのは難しい 権力に飲まれて揺らぐばかり
It's hard to survive pointlessly, just swaying while being swallowed by power
神を引いて絵師神になり変わり 夜叉座で豹変する小物たち
Drawing God and becoming a god-artist, small fries changing completely on the throne
批判に見せかけ自壊の祈り
A prayer of self-destruction disguised as criticism
Do you know?
何見てんのそれ 不細工 見てんのそれ
What are you looking at? Ugly, are you looking at that?
意味がよくわかんないわ 眠たいわ むちゃくちゃよマジ
I don't really get the meaning, I'm sleepy, it's crazy, seriously
飽きっぽいんだおけ？みんな飽きっぽいんだおけ？
Fickle, okay? Everyone is fickle, okay?
踊れるやつちょうだいちょうだいビーム
Give me someone who can dance, give me, give me beam
きしょいね きしょいね それきしょいね きしょいね 逆にファンになってきたじゃん
Gross, isn't it? Gross, isn't it? That's gross, isn't it? Gross, isn't it? Conversely I've become a fan
ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 器ちっちゃいね ちっちゃいね 天才ゆえ孤独ですね
Small, isn't it? Small, isn't it? Your capacity is small, isn't it? Small, isn't it? Lonely because you're a genius, right?
かっけー！
Cool!
ご愁傷様
My condolences
神っぽいなそれ 卑屈 神っぽいなそれ
That's God-ish, submissive, that's God-ish
超健康、健康に果ててくたばっていく感じ
Feeling of ending in super health, health, and dropping dead
野暮っぽいなそれ 卑屈 野暮っぽいなそれ
That's unrefined-ish, submissive, that's unrefined-ish
もう愛執、愛執、ヘビィ五年前のヒール
Already attachment, attachment, heavy heels from five years ago
そのタイトル そのサブタイ そのストーリー その音楽 その歌 そのメロディ
That title, that subtitle, that story, that music, that song, that melody
あれっぽいなそれ 卑屈 あれっぽいなそれ
That's that-ish, submissive, that's that-ish
その名言 その意見 その批評 そのカリスマ そのギャグ そのセンス
That quote, that opinion, that criticism, that charisma, that gag, that sense
神っぽいなそれ 卑屈 ぽいな ぽい 憧れちゃうわ
That's God-ish, submissive, -ish, -ish, I'm starting to admire it
神っぽいな
It's God-ish
愛のネタバレ別れっぽいな
Love spoilers, feels like a breakup
人生のネタバレ死ぬっぽいな
Life spoilers, feels like death
全て理解してわずらった
I understood everything and got sick
無邪気に踊っていたかった人生
A life where I wanted to dance innocently
お前、4年目ってすごくなーい？お祝いだよ。
Your 4th year is amazing, isn't it? Congrats!
お、すげーじゃん。
Oh, that's great.
先輩だから、言っとくけど。一応ね。
I'm your senior, just so you know. Just in case.
一応ね。一応じゃねーわ。
Just in case. It's not "just in case."
お前だいぶ離れとると思っとんねん。お前何期生だお前。
I think we're quite far apart. What generation are you?
ろ、ろ、六期だ。
S-S-Sixth gen.
六期でしょ？こっち二期なんだよ。
Sixth, right? I'm second gen.
ういー。だから何？六の方が強いですけど。
Wee. So what? Six is stronger.
もっと敬えよ！
Show more respect!
大富豪では二が一番強いからな！
In Daifugo, two is the strongest!
おい黙れ！
Hey, shut up!
お前も先輩じゃん。だからさデビュー前？
You're my senior too. So, before my debut?
そう、そうだね。
Yes, that's right.
歌ってみた出す時、被るみたいになった時さ、
あー死んだわ、俺、ってなって。
When our covers overlapped, I was like, "Ah, I'm dead."
え、マジで、どうしようと思って。
Eh, seriously, I was wondering what to do.
なったよな？どうしようってなって、気まずいと思って。
Right? We were like, "What should we do?" It's awkward.
であん時気にしないでほしいなと思って、
チャット送ったのがきっかけやん。
That's when I sent that chat message asking you not to worry about it.
出会い中シオン。
Meeting-obsessed Shion.
何だお前。優しさやろ。優しさやろ。
What are you talking about? It was kindness.
いやーもう今ではね一緒に歌えるようになったね。らぶち。
Well, now we can sing together. Love ya.
歌えるようになったね、あんなに。
We can sing together now, after all that.
ハート作ろうハート。ハート作ろう。ういー。
Let's make a heart. Let's make a heart. Wee.
おたく。逆だろ。
Otaku. It's backwards.
逆だろ。ういー。
It's backwards. Wee.
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。
It's fine, it's fine.
これハートなってる？本当に。
Is this a heart? Really?
なってるだろ。なってる。
It is. It is.
いや、気持ちでいいんだよ、こういうのは。
No, it's the feeling that counts for stuff like this.
お前身長いくつ？
How tall are you?
139だが。
139, but...
ちっちぇー。ういー。
Small. Wee.
でも我が輩の角の方がでかいよ。
But my horns are bigger.
あ、お前帽子取れよ、これ。
Hey, take off your hat.
ほら見て。並んだらさ、ほら見て、ほら。
Look. If we stand side by side, look.
あー、同じくらいじゃん。
Ah, we're about the same.
お前そんなイキれるほどでかくないぞ、それは。
You're not big enough to act so cocky about it.
角取ったらお前こんなしかないだろ、こんな。
If you take off your horns, you're only this big.
いや黙れ。お前イキれるほどそんな変わってないからね。
No, shut up. You haven't changed enough to act cocky.
はいよしよし。うるさいね君ね。
There, there. You're noisy.
ほら、ホロクスの総帥さん。
Look, General of HoloX-san.
何、手懐けた、手懐けた。
What, I tamed you.
総帥さん、初めて言われたけど。やめろ。
That's the first time I've been called "General-san." Stop it.
並ぶな。
Don't stand next to me.
記念写真撮ろう。記念写真撮ろうよ、何する？
Let's take a commemorative photo. What should we do?
一応撮ろうよ、一応。
Let's take one, just in case.
一応って何だよ。
What do you mean "just in case"?
じゃ証明写真撮ろう。我が輩たちの証明写真。正面から。
Then let's take an ID photo. From the front.
お前やば。いつでも見れるよこの絵。
You're crazy. We can see this view anytime.
もっとさ、四周年でさ、記念日じゃん今日は、うちらの記念日ちゃん。
But it's the 4th anniversary, a special day, our special day.
何でお前の記念日になってんだよ。何の関係があるんだよ。
Why did it become your anniversary? What does it have to do with you?
我が輩も入れてよ一緒に。四周年をこっちにしてよ。しょうがないな。
Let me in too. Make it my 4th anniversary too. Fine, I guess.
何する何する？
What should we do?
とりあえず陰キャピースしよ。陰キャピース。
For now, let's do the Introvert Peace.
そうだね、まあ確かに。写真撮る時これしかしないから。
Right, true. I only do this when taking photos.
最近何流行ってんの？ポーズ。
What's popular lately? Poses.
ギャルじゃない？ギャルってどうやんの？
Gyaru? How do you do "Gyaru"?
ギャル。逆ピースみたいな。これ？ギャル？ギャル。
Gyaru. Like a reverse peace. This? Gyaru.
お前ぎこちな！
You're so awkward!
はぁお前、お前、ギャルになりきれてないから。陰キャ。
Hah, you're not fully a Gyaru yet. Introvert.
超可愛い。なんかギャルっぽいね。
Super cute. Somehow it looks Gyaru-ish.
そうですね、ギャルっぽいラストで。
Yes, finishing with a Gyaru-ish look.
しょうもな。他にないのかな、他に。
So dumb. Isn't there anything else?
あれ、あれ、あれするエッチなやつ。上から撮ってもらう。
Let's do that... the sexy one. Have them take it from above.
あーいいじゃん。エッチ、見ないで！もっともっと上から。
Ah, that's good. Sexy, don't look! From even higher.
くねくねしろよお前もっと。我が輩を見ろもう。
Wriggle more! Look at me already.
あ、エロい。ケツだよ、ケツ。
Ah, sexy. It's the butt, the butt.
我が輩の髪の毛長いな。バンされるぞ。
My hair is long. We'll get banned.
あ、やばお前だけな。お前髪の毛長い。
Ah, only you will. Your hair is long.
お前のチャンネルだからいいよ。何でそんなこと言うの。
It's your channel, so it's fine. Why would you say that?
四周年記念日にね。第四回盤。
On the 4th anniversary. The 4th Edition.
いやでもなんかさ3Dいいね、よかったこいつと隣で並べて。
But you know, 3D is great. I'm glad I could stand next to this guy.
そう動き回れるからね。殴れるよもう。ほら。
Yeah, because we can move around. I can punch you now. Take this.
お前ふざけんな。後輩いじめ。
Hey, cut it out. Junior bullying.
後輩いじめになる。
This is junior bullying.
おつぼねかよお前。敬えよ。
Are you some kind of old office lady? Respect me.
実はこうやって裏でやってるのがバレる。
My secret behind-the-scenes actions are being exposed.
違う、ねえ、何してんの。暇なの？嘘だよ。可愛いシオンちゃん。
No, hey, what are you doing? Are you bored? Just kidding. Cute Shion-chan.
誰が可愛いってこと？可愛いんじゃないの。
Who's cute? Aren't you cute?
じゃ、ありがとうね。
Well, thank you.
なんでそんな上からなんだ？
Why are you being so high and mighty?
言うこと全部上からなんだ、どうしてた？
Everything you say is from your high horse. What's up with that?
強いから。
Because I'm strong.
強から...
Because you're strong...
強から。
Because I'm strong.
よわそう。
You seem weak.
楽しかったぞ。
It was fun.
またね。
See ya.
うん、またな。バイバイ。
Yeah, see ya. Bye-bye.
バイバイ、ありがとう。
Bye-bye, thank you.
バイバイ。
Bye-bye.
せーの！
One, two!
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that won't do
もうそんなんじゃほら
Come on, that's not enough
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more
恋愛サーキュレーション
作詞:meg rock 作曲:神前暁
Renai Circulation
Lyrics: meg rock  Composition: Satoru Kosaki
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If putting it into words makes the relationship vanish
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた
Then I thought, it's fine to just erase the words
恐れてた だけどあれ？
I was afraid, but wait, what?
なんか違うかも
Maybe something is different
千里の道も一歩から
Even a thousand-mile journey starts with a single step
石のように固いそんな意志で
With a will as hard as a stone
塵も積もれば大和撫子？
If dust piles up, it becomes a Yamato Nadeshiko?
「し」抜きで いや「死」抜きで
Not excluding the 'shi'... wait, excluding the death!
ふわふわリ ふわふわル
Fluffy-fluffy, fluffy-fluffy
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Just you calling my name makes me float into the air
ふわふわル ふわふわリ
Fluffy-fluffy, fluffy-fluffy
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Just you smiling makes me smile too
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
I'm happy just to have met you
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that won't do
もうそんなんじゃほら
Come on, that's not enough
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more
そうそんなんじゃやだ
Yeah, I don't want that
ねぇそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's not enough yet
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Keep looking at me, forever and ever
私の中のあなたほど
As much as you are within me
あなたの中の私の存在は
My existence within you is...
まだまだ大きくないこともわかってるけれど
I know it's not that big yet, but...
今この同じ瞬間 共有してる時間
Right now, this same moment, this shared time
塵も積もれば大和撫子
If dust piles up, it becomes a Yamato Nadeshiko
略して ちりつもやまとなでこ！
Abbreviated: Chiritsumo Yamato Nadeko!
くらくらリ くらくらル
Dizzy-dizzy, dizzy-dizzy
あなたを見上げたら それだけでまぶしすぎて
Just looking up at you is too dazzling
くらくらル くらくらリ
Dizzy-dizzy, dizzy-dizzy
あなたを想っている それだけで溶けてしまう
Just thinking of you makes me melt away
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
I'm happy just to have met you
コイ・スル・キ・セ・ツ・ハ
The season of love is...
ヨ・ク・バ・リ・サーキュレーション
A greedy circulation
コイ・スル・キ・モ・チ・ハ
The feeling of love is...
ヨ・ク・バ・リ・サーキュレーション
A greedy circulation
コイ・スル・ヒ・ト・ミ・ハ
The eyes of love are...
ヨ・ク・バ・リ・サーキュレーション
A greedy circulation
コイ・スル・オ・ト・メ・ハ
The maiden in love is...
ヨ・ク・バ・リ・サーキュレーション
A greedy circulation
ふわふわリ ふわふわル
Fluffy-fluffy, fluffy-fluffy
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Just you calling my name makes me float into the air
ふわふわル ふわふわリ
Fluffy-fluffy, fluffy-fluffy
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Just you smiling makes me smile too
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's a prank of fate
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
I'm happy just to have met you
でもそんなんじゃだめ
But that won't do
もうそんなんじゃほら
Come on, that's not enough
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart will keep evolving, more and more
そうそんなんじゃやだ
Yeah, I don't want that
ねぇそんなんじゃまだ
Hey, that's not enough yet
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Keep looking at me, forever and ever
Gura!
Hi Shion!
今日は来てくれてありがとう! 会えて嬉しいよ!
Thanks for coming today! I'm happy to see you!
私も! 誘ってくれて...
Me too! Thanks for inviting me...
来てくれてありがとうシオン先輩！
Thanks for coming, Shion-senpai!
1年半前初めて会ってコラボとか歌ってみたとか上げたよね
We met for the first time 1.5 years ago and did collabs and covers together.
うわー、時間が早く経ちますよね
Wow, time really flies, doesn't it?
初めての会話、まだ覚えています
I still remember our first conversation.
あの会話覚え...
I remember that conversation...
ぐら、だめでしょ！
Gura, no! Don't say that!
やっと3Dで会えたね。実際に会ってみてどうかな？
We finally met in 3D. How do you feel meeting in person?
印象とかある？
Any impressions?
うん、はい
Um, yes.
シオン先輩は思ったより背が低いですよね
Shion-senpai is shorter than I thought.
ぐらだって小さいでしょ！
Gura, you're small too!
見せて、見せて
Show me, show me.
やだ、どうしよう。じゃあ、見せようかな先輩
Oh no, what should I do? Well, I guess I'll show you, Senpai.
見せて、くるっと回ってくるっと
Show me, spin around, spin around.
おー、かわいい！
Oh, cute!
かわいい！
So cute!
かわいいー、しっぽがかわいい
So cute! The tail is cute!
おー、かわいい
Oh, cute.
ぐら、写真撮ろうよ
Gura, let's take a photo.
うん、OKです
Yeah, okay.
やったー
Yay!
シオン、ガオ
Shion, Gao!
ガオ
Gao!
次はなにする？
What's next?
ハート
Heart.
ハート、イエーイ
Heart, yay!
じゃあ、ラストは...
Well, last is...
どやー
Doya!
どや
Doya.
GO! GO! MANIAC
やばい、止まらない、止まらない
No way, I can't stop, I can't stop
昼に夜に朝に Sing a song
Morning, night, afternoon, Sing a song
好きなことしてるだけだよ GO! GO! MANIAC
I'm just doing what I love, GO! GO! MANIAC
あのメロディ、このリリック
That melody, these lyrics
探していきたいんだもっともっと
I want to keep searching for more and more
みんな一緒にね Chance! 願いは Jump!
Everyone together, Chance! Wishes Jump!
駆け抜けて Hop! 想いは Step!
Run through Hop! Feelings Step!
伝えよう Music! ハート ここにしてもっかい
Let's convey Music! Heart, put it here once more
誰でも持ってるハートという名の小宇宙
Everyone has a microcosm called a heart
眠っているよ 喜怒哀楽や愛
Joy, anger, sorrow, pleasure, and love are sleeping there
瞬間当たりにワクワクを教えてたり美人
Teaching excitement in an instant, a beauty
感慨満載の日々 歌にしちゃおう ぶちまけちゃおう
Days full of deep emotion, let's make them into a song, let's pour it all out
追求しちゃう無意識に 研究されニュース
Unconsciously pursuing, being researched as news
エアでOK 雰囲気重視で 刻むリズム 悔いはない毎日
It's okay with air, focusing on the atmosphere, carving the rhythm, no regrets in everyday life
Enjoy 楽しんだもん勝ち
Enjoy, the one who has fun wins
ごめん 譲れない 譲らない
Sorry, I can't give in, I won't give in
縦横無尽に Sing a song
Freely in all directions, Sing a song
好きな音でしてるだけだよ GO! GO! MANIAC
I'm just doing it with sounds I like, GO! GO! MANIAC
あのグルーヴ、このリバーブ
That groove, this reverb
試していきたいんだずっとずっと
I want to keep trying it forever and ever
息合わせてね Shake! 瞳で Dash!
Sync our breath, Shake! Dash with your eyes!
強気に Shake! 盛り上がろう
Shake strongly! Let's get excited
浴びたら忘れられない 喝采
Once you bask in it, you'll never forget the applause
本当現実は待ったなし 小説より
Really, reality waits for no one, more than a novel
音に暮らしてても ぶつかる出会い
Even if I live in sound, I encounter clashes
急転当たりにグッときたりシンパシー
Getting moved by sudden turns, sympathy
何これって運命じゃ 溺れちゃおう 目一杯楽しんじゃおう
Is this fate? Let's drown in it, let's have as much fun as we can
次元超えても通常通り 引き下げない Friendship
Even crossing dimensions, normal as always, won't lower my friendship
約束してないのに つい集まる ホットなメンバー
Even though we didn't promise, we always gather, the hot members
相当抜群 衝突して聞こえるよな ガン
Quite outstanding, it sounds like we're colliding, Bang!
飛べ 笑顔ピカ 笑顔でね
Fly, sparkling smiles, with a smile
晴れも曇りも Ups and downs
Sunny or cloudy, Ups and downs
好きな人といるだけだよ GO! GO! MANIAC
I'm just with the people I love, GO! GO! MANIAC
あのハーモニー、このパーティー
That harmony, this party
受け止めていきたいの 即断即決
I want to accept it, quick decision
目合わせてね Chance! 心の View!
Meet our eyes, Chance! View of the heart!
重ねて Blue! 輝くわ
Layered Blue! It shines
まだまだいけるはずよ 正真正銘
We should still be able to go, genuine
...もっと チャンスを
...more, chances!
チャンスを もっと チャンスを
Chances, even more chances!
想いを もっと 伝えよう
Let's convey our feelings more!
ワンワン 想いを もっと 伝えよう
Bow-wow, let's convey our feelings more!
気持ちから イェーイ！アンコール！ もっかい！
From the heart, yay! Encore! One more time!
Oh my no-no music no life, oh my no-no when all right
Oh my no-no soft way, baby have a favorite, so
Oh my no-no soft way, baby have a favorite, I love!
はい！というわけで、GO! GO! MANIACでしたー！いえーい！
Alright! So, that was 'GO! GO! MANIAC'! Yay!
ねぇ、みなさん、ずっと気になってた...「え、後ろになんか化け物いるじゃん」って思ってたでしょ？
Hey, everyone, you've been wondering...
"Hey, there's some kind of monster behind her," right?
一人ずつ見ちゃおう。
Let's take a look at them one by one.
こいつね。こいつ頑張ってね。絶対それ弾けないじゃんみたいな手の短さで頑張ってね。どうやって弾いてたんでしょうか。
This one here. He's doing his best.
Doing his best with such short arms that look like they couldn't possibly play.
I wonder how he was playing.
どうやって弾いてたんでしょうか彼は。頑張って弾いてくれてます。
I wonder how he was playing. He's trying his hardest for us.
かわいいね、かわいいね、踏みたい。踏みたい可愛さしてるね。いいね。
So cute, so cute, I want to step on him.
He's got that "step-on-me" kind of cuteness. Nice.
こいつね。ねぇ、君どうやって叩いてたの？叩けるの、それ？
This one. Hey, how were you drumming?
Can you even hit those?
あ、叩けるね！かわいいね！ふふ、肉球みたいな、肉球あるじゃん。かわいい。
Oh, he can hit them! So cute!
Hehe, like little paw pads, he's got paw pads. Cute.
ねぇ、みんな、これさ、なんか頑張ってるときさ、こうやってクイクイしながら頑張ってたじゃん。
Hey, everyone, while he was working hard,
he was doing this wiggling thing, right?
この顔がいいよね、頑張ってますみたいな。ね、頑張ってますね。
This face is great, like "I'm doing my best."
Yeah, he's really trying hard.
かわいいー。
So cute.
次ね。これ、えーと、何て言うんだっけ...ドラムだ、ドラム！思い出した、ドラムだ。かわいい。
Next. This, uh, what do you call it...
It's the drums, the drums! I remembered, it's the drums. Cute.
こいつね、こいつベース。こいつもね、あのキーボードの人と一緒で、どうやって弾いてんねん、みたいな。
And this one's the bass.
Just like the keyboardist, it's like, "How are you playing that?"
こんな、こんなちっちゃな手でどうやって弾いてんのこれ。
How are you playing with such tiny hands?
どうやって弾いてんの。ねぇ。弾けるの？
How are you playing it? Hey. Can you really play?
絶対届かないじゃん。あー、頑張って、あー頑張ってたのそうやって。あーそうやって頑張ってたの。絶対弾けてませんと。
There's no way you can reach. Oh, you're trying...
Oh, so that's how you were trying. He definitely can't play it.
めっちゃかわいいね。こうやって頑張ってたんだよ。
He's so cute. He was trying his best like that.
いやー、GO! GO! MANIACね、あのー、本当にめちゃめちゃ頑張って覚えたんだけど、歌、歌を。
Wow, 'GO! GO! MANIAC'...
I really worked incredibly hard to memorize the song.
そもそも歌をめっちゃ頑張って覚えたの。どこが一番大変だったかって言うと、あの最後のドラムのパート...
I worked really hard on the vocals in the first place.
As for what was the hardest part... that drum part at the end...
ドラムじゃねーわ、何だ、ドラムじゃない、あの、何だっけ、英語の...
It wasn't the drums, what was it... not the drums, it was... the English part!
トゥルンテッテッテッテッみたいなところ、めちゃめちゃ頑張って覚えた、どうやって覚えたかって言うと、カタカナで歌詞に書いて、
The part that goes like 'turun-te-te-te-te'. I worked so hard on it.
I memorized it by writing out the lyrics in Katakana.
ね、聞こえる、こうやって聞こえるなーっていうのを歌詞に書いて、頑張って覚えたんだよ。めちゃ大変だったんだからね。
I'd write down how it sounded to me and worked hard to memorize it.
It was really tough, you know!
あとダンスもね！見た？みんな。ダンスも頑張ってた。ダンスも覚えるの大変だったんだからね。
And the dance too! Did you see it, everyone?
I worked hard on the dance too. Memorizing it was really difficult.
あのね、振り付けを考えてもらったんだけど、Cメロのね、あのこう足を、こう足をさ、こうやってチョコンって、こうやってやったところがね、
I had the choreography made for me,
and in the bridge, when I went like this with my feet...
可愛かったね、可愛い振り付けだった。
It was so cute, the choreography was adorable.
いやー、可愛くて、ちょっとみんな、惚れちゃ...惚れられたら困っちゃう。
It was so cute, I'm worried you all might... fall in love with me.
ね、というわけで、GO! GO! MANIACでした。可愛い曲だよね。シオもね、ちょっと前にけいおんを見始めて、まだね、あの全部見れてないね、ちょっと長くて。
Anyway, that was 'GO! GO! MANIAC'. It's a cute song, right?
I started watching 'K-ON!' a while ago, but I haven't finished it yet because it's long.
長くて、ちょっと最近ちょっとね、まだ見れてないんだけど、めちゃいいな、けいおんね。そう、けいおんさんの曲でした。
It's long, so I haven't been able to watch it lately,
but 'K-ON!' is really good. So yeah, that was a 'K-ON!' song.
というわけで、この後はね、あのー、実は...みんな衝撃の事実かもしんないんだけど...
So, after this... actually, this might be shocking to everyone...
なんと！グッズが出るんですね！
Believe it or not, we're releasing new merchandise!
というわけで、宣伝担当の紫咲シオンさん、お願いしまーす！
And now, I'll turn it over to the PR representative,
Murasaki Shion!
紫咲シオン 活動4周年記念 8月17日 販売開始
Murasaki Shion 4th Anniversary Celebration - Sales begin August 17th
はーい！宣伝担当の紫咲シオンです！
Hello! I'm the PR rep, Murasaki Shion!
今日はみんなに嬉しい、嬉しい、グッズのお知らせです！
Today, I have some very happy news about merchandise for everyone!
ということでやって参りましたー！
And so, here we are!
イェーイ！
Yay!
拍手ーということで、
Applause! And so...
えー活動4周年記念グッズがこの後22時から発売開始ということで...
...the 4th Anniversary merch will go on sale starting at 10 PM tonight!
めちゃまずもうね、見ての通りめちゃくちゃ可愛いこの、もうイラストがね、
First off, as you can see, this illustration is just so cute!
イラストの時点でえっ可愛い綺麗すぎ美しすぎというコメントが絶対流れてると思います。
I'm sure the comments are already flooded with "So cute!", "So pretty!", and "So beautiful!"
はははは！
(Laughs)
はいということでね、見ていきましょうグッズの方を。
Alright then, let's take a look at the merchandise.
はい、まず1つ目！
Okay, first up!
塩っ子ブルゾン！
The Shiokko Blouson!
これはですね、みんなに外で着て欲しくて、外で着れるようなシンプル目なデザインを...
I really wanted everyone to wear this outside, so I came up with a simple design...
...めちゃめちゃ一生懸命考えました。
...that I worked really hard on.
めっちゃ形とかね、こだわって、色とかにもめっちゃこだわったんですよ。
I was really particular about the shape and the colors.
まずね見ていきましょう、胸の刺繍デザイン！
Let's check it out, the embroidered design on the chest!
で、これね、紫シオン、シオンのあのこのね髪型の顔、顔っていうか髪型がね、あのついてて真ん中にSということで。
It features my hairstyle with an "S" in the middle. Murasaki Shion's signature look!
めっちゃ良い！もうめっちゃ良い！
It's so good! Seriously, it's great!
これが刺繍されてあの胸の部分にねつくわけなんです。めっちゃ良い。
This will be embroidered right on the chest part. It's so cool.
ちなみにあのサンプルのね形もちゃんと見たんですけど、めちゃくちゃ良かった。
By the way, I saw the sample, and the shape was absolutely perfect.
で裏にね、タグ！タグ！ブランドっぽい！
And on the inside, there's a tag! A tag! It feels like a real brand!
紫シオンブランド！みたいな感じでタグデザインが入ってますね。
The "Murasaki Shion Brand"! That's the kind of tag design it has.
めちゃ良いじゃん！紫シオンって書いてある、もうめっちゃ良い！
Isn't it great? It says "Murasaki Shion". I love it!
これをみんなに着て欲しいんです。
I really want everyone to wear this.
これもう会社に行く時、ね、いつでももうどこでも...
Whether you're going to work, or anywhere else...
...いつでもどこでも身につけて、出かける時にも身につけてって欲しいなと思って外に出れるようなデザインにしました。
...I wanted a design that you could wear anytime, anywhere, so I made it wearable for going out.
フリーサイズで出来てます。
It's available in free size.
でこれ本当に着て、マジでお願い！一生のお願い。
So please wear it, I'm serious! It's the request of a lifetime.
嘘、一生に30回目ぐらいのお願い。
Wait, more like the 30th "request of a lifetime" this year.
次！
Next!
一緒にお出かけリバーシブルトートバッグ！
The "Go Out Together" Reversible Tote Bag!
めちゃ可愛い。これはねあのキービジュアルの、あの最初にね出てきた画像イラストの、
It's so cute. This features the key visual illustration from the beginning...
えーリバーシブルトートバッグということでね、もうこれめっちゃ良い。
...on a reversible tote bag. It's really nice.
何が良いかって言うと、まずイラストの部分が、イラストが前面に書いてある方の、えートートバッグのデザインと、
What's great is that one side has the illustration covering the entire front...
裏返したら、あのBになって、この黒いね、黒い真っ黒のところにこのロゴ、
...and if you flip it over to side B, it's a solid black...
紫シオン、シオン of the logo がね入ってる。めちゃ可愛いよねこのロゴ。
...with the "Murasaki Shion" logo on it. This logo is so cute, right?
めちゃ可愛い。これだから、あの、ちょっとえっ今日はちょっとあの、
It's so cute. So, for example...
ちょっと大事な大事な用事、大事な用事の時には持ってってください。
...please take it with you for those really important occasions.
今日は大事な用事だからあのちょっとシンプル目な方で行かないとっていう時はこのBで、
When you need to go with something simpler for an important meeting, use side B.
もう今日もうシオンちゃんもう大好きすぎもう全面に押し出していこうっていう時はねもうAでねぜひ持ち歩いてください。
But when you want to show your full love for Shion, definitely go with side A!
めちゃ可愛いあのさっきのブルゾンと合わせて持ち運んでください。
It's so cute! Please carry it along with the blouson from earlier.
めちゃ可愛い、もうめっちゃ可愛い。大絶賛。
It's just so cute. I'm totally in love with it.
次！
Next!
ランダムラバーストラップ！
The Random Rubber Strap!
はい、これもね、めちゃ可愛いよね。もう可愛いしか言えないんだけど、可愛いのもしょうがないんじゃん？
Yes, this is also super cute. I can't stop saying "cute", but I can't help it!
ということでね、あの4種類からランダムに1種類入ってますよということで。はい。
There are four types, and you'll get one at random. Yes.
えっこれね、めちゃ可愛いよね。
Wow, this is really cute.
あのね、シオン的には一番右のやつが、もうめっちゃ可愛い、塩っ子ギュッて抱いてて。
Personally, I find the one on the far right the cutest, hugging a Shiokko.
もうこの塩っ子... なんかさ塩っ子ってさ、リスナーなわけじゃん。
And this Shiokko... well, the Shiokko are the listeners, right?
ね。ちょっと、なんかリスナーとギュッしちゃってちょっと、炎上しちゃいますよ！はははは！
So, hugging a listener... might cause a bit of a scandal! (Laughs)
めちゃ可愛いんだけど。シオン的にはこの右のやつがね一番おすすめというか可愛い。
But it's just so cute. The one on the right is my top recommendation.
全部可愛いんだけど一番好きなんだよね。
They're all cute, but that one's my favorite.
あとねこのゴスロリシオンもね、めちゃ可愛いね。
Also, the Goth-Loli Shion is super cute too.
えっ全部可愛いな。全部手に入れてね、あのトートバッグにジャラジャラつけて欲しいですね、あの。はい。
Wow, they're all cute. I hope you get them all and hang them all over your tote bag! Yes.
ぜん、あの、昔のね、ちょっと前のグッズでアクキーとかね缶バッジもあったから、
We had acrylic keychains and badges in past merch as well...
そういうグッズをねいっぱいトートバッグにつけて持ち運んで欲しいなという思いからランダムラバーストラップ、
...so I wanted you to decorate your tote bag with all those goods, hence the random rubber straps.
今回はラバーストラ、ちょっと噛み噛み...ラバーストラップになっております。
And this time, it's rubber stra... I'm tripping over my words... rubber straps.
はい、ということで！なんと！なんと！ななななんと！
Alright, and finally! Can you believe it?!
フルセット購入特典、星先生描き下ろしポストカードに、
As a bonus for buying the full set, you'll get a postcard illustrated by Hoshi-sensei...
えー数量限定で直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます。
...plus a limited-edition postcard with a handwritten signature and foil-stamped message!
こちら数量限定なんですけど、めちゃくちゃ多いから、めちゃくちゃ多いんだよ。
It's limited, but I've prepared a ton of them. A whole lot!
めっちゃあの、頑張るつもりで、頑張るつもりで、頑張るつもりで、あの、多くしたので、
I really put in the effort and signed as many as I possibly could...
あの、ぜひあの余らない、余らなかったら、余らないように、たくさん皆さんあの手に入れてください、紫シオンのサインを。
...so please, make sure they don't go to waste and get your hands on my signature!
あんまやんない、本当にいつぶりだってぐらい結構久しぶりの直筆サインなんですけど。
I don't do this often. It's been quite a while since I've done handwritten signatures.
たぶんねこの先もね、あんまやる回数ないと思うから、ぜひここでバッチリ手に入れて欲しいですね。まあ数量限定なんですけど。
I probably won't be doing this much in the future either, so please grab one now! Though they are limited.
はい！
Yes!
えー、買えなかった人用にも、えー、
Uh, for those who couldn't buy the individual items...
フルセットで箔押しサイン&メッセージ入りポストカードがついてきます。
the full set comes with a foil-stamped signature and message postcard.
こっちはね、あの、金で、金のいつもの箔押しになっていて、
This one has the usual gold foil stamping,
メッセージ何が入ってるかわからないよーみたいな感じになっていると思います。
and you won't know what message is inside until you see it.
ぜひ、あの、よろしくお願いします。手に入れてください、絶対に。全て。
So please, look forward to it. Please get them, definitely. All of them.
全て身に纏ってるところをシオン見たいので、あの、ぜひ届いたら
Shion wants to see you all wearing everything, so please,
全身の写真でもTwitterに載せてください。見たいです。
post photos of yourself in the full gear on Twitter when they arrive. I want to see!
はい、以上の4点ですね。
Alright, that's all four items.
あの、ポストカードも合わせて、4点となっております。
Including the postcard, there are four items in total.
こちら、ぜひ手に入れてくださいね、皆さん。はい、返事は？
Please make sure to get these, everyone. Okay, what's your answer?
はーい！
Yes!
というわけで、この後22時からグッズの方もよろしくお願いします。チェックしてください。
And so, the merch will be available from 10 PM. Please check it out.
そして、なんと、さらに、もう一つ。
And then, what's more, there's one more thing.
重大告知が、この後、あるかも！
There might be a major announcement coming up next!
以上、宣伝担当の紫咲シオンでしたー！
That's all from the PR manager, Murasaki Shion!
はい！というわけで宣伝担当の紫咲シオンさんでした。
Alright! That was Murasaki Shion-san, the PR manager.
ね、みんなグッズちゃんと見てた？
Hey, did everyone see the merch properly?
ね、トートバッグと、
So, the tote bag,
ブルゾンと、
the blouson,
ランダムラバーストラップと、
the random rubber strap,
あとね、特典で、あの数量限定で直筆サイン入りポストカード、
and as a bonus, the limited quantity handwritten signature postcard,
えっと、数量限定じゃないほうが、複製のね、メッセージが入ってるポストカードです。
and the one that's not limited has a printed message on the postcard.
え、みんなにね、ブルゾンを着てほしくてね、頑張って考えました、あのデザインとかね。
I really wanted everyone to wear the blouson, so I worked hard on the design.
デザインどうしよう？みたいなので。考えたのでみんな着てね。あれ。
I was like, "What should I do for the design?" I thought about it, so please wear it.
あれ着て、中にハバ卒Tシャツ着て、お出かけするんだよ。
Wear that over your graduation T-shirt and go out.
あれでみんなは仕事に行くの、これから毎日。わかった？
You all should go to work in that from now on, every day. Got it?
ね、可愛かったでしょ。あとトートバッグもね、ちょっとトートバッグ握りしめて、
Right, it was cute, wasn't it? And the tote bag too. Grip that tote bag tightly,
あれ着て、ラバーストラップをトートバッグにジャラジャラいっぱい付けて、毎日仕事行くからね、みんな。これから。
wear that, put tons of rubber straps on your tote bag, and go to work every day, okay? From now on.
頑張ってね、お仕事。うふふふ。
Good luck with your work. Hehehe.
はい、というわけで皆さんぜひグッズの方もね、チェックしてください。
Alright, so everyone, please make sure to check out the merch too.
で、ここで紫咲シオンから...
And now, from Murasaki Shion...
非常に残念...じゃねーわ！
a very disappointing... Wait, no!
非常に大事な、大事な重大告知があります。
a very important, very major announcement.
この後、なんと、Kanariaさん描き下ろしの新曲、オリジナル曲、
After this, I'm going to sing a brand new original song written by Kanaria-san,
シャンデリア歌います！
"Chandelier"!
びっくりしたでしょう。みんな、それではぜひ聞いてください。
You were surprised, weren't you? Alright everyone, please listen to it.
シャンデリア。
Chandelier.
行き場ない情熱と苦しさを君からもらってシャラララララ
Give me your aimless passion and pain, sha-la-la-la-la-la
衝動からは抗えないわ
I can't resist these impulses
あとちょっとそうずっとえっと、君都合とは譲れないわ
Just a bit more, forever, well... I won't give in to your convenience
叶わないわ
It won't come true
あとちょっとの距離イメージ、君都合とは飾らないわ
Imagining just a bit more distance, I won't dress up for your convenience
忘れないわ、まだまだ
I won't forget, not yet
ラッキー、ザンキー、ハッピーだらだら
Lucky, Zanky, Happy, idle
くも切ったマイウェイなら一度きりさまた一度ね、お願いぎゅっとハグして
If I cut through the clouds on my way, it's just once... once more, please hug me tight
ラッキー、ザンキー、ハッピーはたまた、くも切ってマイウェイなら
Lucky, Zanky, Happy, or perhaps... if I cut through the clouds on my way
お願い聞いて頭が良いんでしょう
Please listen to me, you're smart, aren't you?
叶わないナイナイの妬み相
It won't come true, this phase of endless envy
行き場ない情熱と痛みも、君から奪ってシャラララララ
Give me your aimless passion and pain, sha-la-la-la-la-la
衝動からは逃げられないわ
I can't escape these impulses
ハッピー、ハッピー、ハッピー、ばたばた前を向いて歩い
Happy, happy, happy, flapping about, walking forward
なら一度きりさまた一度ね、お願いよっとラブリーな
Then it's just once... once more, please, give me something lovely
ラッキー、ザンキー、ハッピーまだまだ、会いに会いに会いに会いに
Lucky, Zanky, Happy, still... coming to see you, see you, see you, see you
お願い聞いてはなはだしいでしょう
Please listen to me, it's excessive, isn't it?
叶わないナイナイの妬み相
It won't come true, this phase of endless envy
行き場ない情熱と痛みと、君からもらってシャラララララ
Taking your aimless passion and pain, sha-la-la-la-la-la
衝動からは抗えないわ
I can't resist these impulses
心の底まで近づいてまだ、愛対する恋をするデザイア
Getting close to the bottom of your heart, the desire for an opposing love
心の底まで二人で近づいてほら
Look, both of us getting close to the bottom of our hearts
衝動からは抗えないわ
I can't resist these impulses
シャンデリア
Chandelier
#紫咲シオン4周年記念
#MurasakiShion4thAnniversary
Murasaki Shion 4th Anniversary Live
はい！というわけで
Yes! And with that...
シャンデリアどうだったでしょうか？
...how did you like Chandelier?
この後すぐ22時から
Right after this, at 22:00...
シャンデリアのMVがプレミア公開されます！
...the MV for Chandelier will have its premiere!
22時からですよ！
It's at 22:00!
この後すぐですよ！
It's right after this!
ぜひ見てくださいね、全員！
Everyone, please be sure to watch it!